<dc:identifier id="epub-id-1">urn:isbn:978-94-92171-01-6</dc:identifier>
<meta refines="#epub-id-1" property="identifier-type" scheme="onix:codelist5">01</meta>
<dc:title id="epub-title-1">The Volkskrant Building: Manufacturing Difference in Amsterdam’s
Creative City</dc:title>
<meta refines="#epub-title-1" property="title-type">main</meta>
<dc:publisher>Amsterdam Creative Industries Publishing</dc:publisher>    
<dc:date id="epub-date">2014-11</dc:date>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:creator id="epub-creator-1">Boukje Cnossen</dc:creator>
<meta refines="#epub-creator-1" property="role" scheme="marc:relators">aut</meta>
<dc:creator id="epub-creator-1">Sebastian Olma</dc:creator>
<meta refines="#epub-creator-1" property="role" scheme="marc:relators">aut</meta>
<dc:contributor id="epub-contributor-1">Miriam Rasch</dc:contributor>
<meta refines="#epub-contributor-1" property="role" scheme="marc:relators">pro</meta>
<dc:contributor id="epub-contributor-2">Margarita Osipian</dc:contributor>
<meta refines="#epub-contributor-2" property="role" scheme="marc:relators">edt</meta>
<dc:contributor id="epub-contributor-3">UNDOG</dc:contributor>
<meta refines="#epub-contributor-3" property="role" scheme="marc:relators">dsr</meta>
<dc:contributor id="epub-contributor-4">André Castro</dc:contributor>
<meta refines="#epub-contributor-4" property="role" scheme="marc:relators">dsr</meta>
<dc:rights>Creative Commons Attribution, NonCommercial, ShareAlike 3.0 Unported (CC BY-NC-SA 3.0)</dc:rights>
<dc:subject>creative class, city, Amsterdam, Volkskrant Building, capital, Sebastian Olma, Boukje Cnossen, Amsterdam Creative Industries Network, creative industries, Hogeschool van Amsterdam, Knowledge Mile, squatting, movement, history, scene, entrepreneur, artists, activism, property developer, hotel, infrastructure, citizenship, creativity, municipality, art factory, broedplaats, club, eighties, transformation, network, production, Richard Sennett, Peter Sloterdijk, philosophy, interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:description>The Volkskrant building more than any other place exemplifies
Amsterdam’s transformation into a ‘creative city’ over the past fifteen
years. Boukje Cnossen and Sebastian Olma trace the history of this
infamous and inspiring place from its deep roots in the squatting heyday
of the eighties to its present renaissance as the Volkshotel. The focus
of their entertaining yet rigorous analysis is the period from 2007 to
2014 when the Volkskrant building hosted an art factory (<i>broedplaats</i>)
run by the former squatters collective Urban Resort.

Artists, activists, city officials, entrepreneurs, and property
developers share their stories of the good times and the struggles in
and around the Volkskrant building. How did a group of former squatters
turn it into a place for both creative entrepreneurship and subversion?
And how could it happen that this countercultural project ended up
attracting the attention of one of the largest property investors in the
Netherlands?

This detailed inquiry into the practices and interests shaping the
epicenter of Amsterdam's creative scene provides a look behind the shiny
façade of creative city policy. The authors show how the Volkskrant
building came to be more than a space for creativity alone, as it opened
up the possibility for a new infrastructure of citizenship.
</dc:description>



